Welcome back.
欢迎回来。
In this step, let's try and add a little bit more complexity into our Functionality.
在这一步，让我们尝试在我们的功能中增加一点复杂性。
What we'd want to do is, we would want to print squares of numbers.
我们想做的是，我们想打印正方形的数字。
Until now, we have been printing the numbers as is.
到目前为止，我们一直在打印数字的原样。
How about printing the squares of each of these numbers?
那么，打印每个数字的正方形呢？
How do we do that?
我们如何做到这一点呢？
Let's look at that.
我们来看看这个。
So, I'll copy this method out. I'll say printSquaresofEvenNumbers.
所以，我将这个方法复制出来。我会说 printSquaresofEvenNumbers。
So let's print squares only of the even numbers in the list.
所以我们只打印列表中偶数的方块。
So, we have a stream, we are allowing only the even numbers to go through, and then printing them.
所以，我们有一个流，我们只允许偶数通过，然后打印它们。
However, over here, we would want to actually print the squares of the numbers.
然而，在这里，我们想实际打印这些数字的方块。
How do I do that? The way I can do that is by doing something called a mapping.
我如何做到这一点呢？我可以做的方法是做一个叫做映射的东西。
So, what we'd want to do is, we would want to map each of the element, we would want to take each of the
所以，我们要做的是，我们要映射每个元素，我们要把每个元素的
element and map it to the square of the element.
元素，并将其映射到该元素的平方。
So, we'd want to calculate the square of the each element and then print the square of the element.
所以，我们要计算每个元素的平方，然后打印元素的平方。
So, how do we do the mapping? The way we can do the mapping is by saying map
那么，我们如何做这个映射呢？我们做映射的方法是通过说map
and you can define the mapper function in here,
你可以在这里定义映射函数、
the mapper lambda expression in here. The mapper lambda expression is, take x or take any number,
mapper lambda expression在这里。mapper lambda表达式是，取x或取任何数字、
and once you have the number, what we would want to do with the number? We would want to actually multiply
一旦你有了这个数字，我们想对这个数字做什么？我们想把它乘以
it by itself.
它本身。
So, number * number.
所以，数字*数字。
So, this expression is called a mapping expression, where we are mapping a number to number into a number.
所以，这个表达式被称为映射表达式，我们将一个数字映射到一个数字中。
The result of this is at the end of it. The number would be multiplied by itself.
这个的结果在它的最后。这个数字会被自己乘以。
So, we'll calculate the square of the number.
所以，我们会计算出这个数字的平方。
And after that, the square would be printed.
而后，这个平方会被打印出来。
Let's try and run this. Oops.
让我们试着运行这个。哎呀。
We have not changed the call in here.
我们没有改变这里的调用。
So, we don't want to print even numbers in the list. We would want to print the squares of all numbers.
所以，我们不希望打印列表中的偶数。我们想打印所有数字的正方形。
So, let's do this, printSquaresOfEvenNumbersInListFunctional and let's run this. Run Java application
所以，让我们这样做，printSquaresOfEvenNumbersInListFunctional，让我们运行这个。运行Java应用程序
and you can see that squares of all the numbers are being printed out.
你可以看到所有数字的正方形都被打印出来了。
Now, you can pause the video in here and try and do a few more things as an exercise. The two exercises
现在，你可以在这里暂停视频，试着再做一些事情作为练习。这两个练习
are Exercise 5 and Exercise 6.
是练习5和练习6。
Exercise 5 is to print the cubes of only the odd numbers. A cube is nothing, but a number multiplied
练习5是只打印奇数的立方体。一个立方体是什么，只是一个数字乘以
by itself three times.
的三倍。
So, three cube is equal to three into three into three, which is 27. Exercise 6 is to print the
所以，三个立方体等于三进三进三，也就是27。练习6是要打印
number of characters in each course name.
每个课程名称中的字符数。
So, I would want to print six characters.
所以，我想打印六个字符。
Here it would be 11 characters,
这里将是11个字符、
here it would be three. So, instead of printing the course itself,
这里是3个。所以，不要打印课程本身、
I would want to print the number of characters in that.
我想打印其中的字符数。
Now, you can pause the video in here and try those two things as an exercise.
现在，你可以暂停这里的视频，尝试这两件事作为练习。
Let's go ahead and solve them.
让我们继续并解决它们。
So, what we would want to do in the exercise is, I'm in FP01Exercises.java.
所以，我们在练习中要做的是，我在FP01Exercises.java中。
And what we'd want to do is, printCubesOfOddNumbers. And the way I can do that is very simple, right?
我们要做的是，printCubesOfOddNumbers。我做这个的方法很简单，对吗？
I would want to map each element, each number which is present in there.
我想映射每个元素，每个存在于其中的数字。
What do I want to do with it?
我想对它做什么？
I'd want to multiply by itself three times, number * number * number.
我想把它乘以三倍，数字*数字*数字。
That's it.
就这样了。
Let's take this and let's use the list of numbers which we have already created and call this in here by
让我们使用我们已经创建的数字列表，并在这里通过传递数字来调用它。
passing in numbers.
传入数字。
Let's see what would be happening. Run Java Application.
让我们看看会发生什么。运行Java应用程序。
The code is a little messy.
这段代码有点乱。
So you can see that only for the odd numbers, the cubes are being printed.
所以你可以看到，只有奇数的方块被打印出来了。
Don't really worry about what's printed after this. This is a result from the courses stuff which is after
不要担心这之后打印的东西。这是课程内容的结果，在这之后
this.
这个。
So, that's cool.
所以，这很好。
We are now able to do the cubes of odd numbers.
我们现在可以做奇数的立方体了。
The next exercise was to actually print the length of these courses.
接下来的练习是实际打印这些课程的长度。
How do we print the length of these courses? Let's look at it right now. So what do we want to do?
我们如何打印这些课程的长度？让我们现在就来看看。那么我们要怎么做呢？
courses.stream().
courses.stream()。
We don't really want to filter anything. For all the courses, what do we want to do?
我们并不真的想过滤什么。对于所有的课程，我们想做什么？
We'd want to print the length. So, we can map each of the courses. So each of the course,
我们想打印长度。所以，我们可以映射每一个课程。所以，每一个课程、
what do we want to map it to?
我们想把它映射到什么？
We'd want to map it to course.length(). So, map
我们想把它映射到course.length()。所以，将
course to course.length() .forEach(System.out::println). Isn't it cool?
到 course.length() .forEach(System.out::println)。这不是很酷吗？
Let's not really worry about this.
让我们不要真的担心这个问题。
Let's comment this out.
让我们把它注释出来。
And let's run this code.
让我们运行这段代码。
You can see, over here, that this is printing the lengths of each one of this. Just to be really really
你可以看到，在这里，这是在打印每个人的长度。只是为了非常非常
clear,
清楚、
what we'll do is, we'll append the course with the space and the course.length().
我们要做的是，在课程中加入空格和course.length()。
So, what we are doing in here is, course + " "
所以，我们在这里所做的是，course + " "
+ course.length. Let's run this.
+ course.length。让我们运行这个。
You can see that it's printing Spring 6, Spring Boot 11 characters,
你可以看到，它正在打印Spring 6，Spring Boot 11个字符、
API is 3 characters, and so on and so forth.
API是3个字符，以此类推。
As we discussed before, it's very very important to get your hands dirty with functional programming.
正如我们之前所讨论的，在函数式编程中动手操作是非常非常重要的。
We are used to doing the traditional approach for a number of years
我们多年来习惯于使用传统的方法
and there is a lot of unlearning to do before we would get comfortable with functional programming.
而在我们适应函数式编程之前，有很多事情要做。
I hope you're having a lot of fun and I'll see you in the next step. Until then,
我希望你玩得很开心，我们下一步再见。直到那时、
bye bye.
bye bye。